Historical Reason Text
 ----------------------------------
The central festival of Christianity is Easter, on which Christians celebrate their belief that Jesus Christ rose from the dead on the third day after his crucifixion. Even for Easter, however, there is no agreement among the various Christian traditions regarding the date or manner of the observance, less for Christmas, Pentecost, or various other holidays. Both Protestants and Catholics observe certain festivals commemorating events in the life of Christ. Of these, the two most important are Christmas, which commemorates the Birth of Jesus, and Easter, which marks his resurrection. 
Christian Religious Calendar for 2019
The Christian holidays are mainly focused on the life of Jesus. Some festivals, like Christmas Day, happen on the same date every year, while others move around within a range of dates. Here we have provided the dates of the Christian religious holidays for calendar year 2019. Christianity was founded in the early 1st century AD, with the teaching, miracle and rebirth of Jesus. Today this is the largest religion in the world with more than 2 billion followers. The Goal of Christianity is about personal relationships: with God and with others. When Jesus was asked to summarize his religion, he said that it was loving God and our neighbor. The Bible is the primary scripture of Christianity. Some of the key aspects of Christian life are:
   - Fellowship with God
   - Our relationships with others 
   - Obedience to God's commands 
   - Discipline