Christian Religious Calendar for 2019
Hindu festivals are celebrated as per the Hindu Calendar. This calendar depends on the movement of sun and moon so most of the festivals are celebrated on different dates, move around within a range of dates in different years. Here we have provided the dates of the Hindu religious holidays for calendar year 2015 & 2016. A Hindu is a follower of Hinduism. Hinduism is believed to be one of the world's oldest organized religions. Hinduism is the world's third largest religion with more than a billion followers. Majority of Hindu people live in India and Nepal. Nowadays large Hindu populations can be found in various parts of the world. Hinduism has no single prophet, no single scripture, and not any one set of religious rites. Most Hindus worship one or more deities, believe in rebirth and value the practice of meditation. Hindu sacred texts are regarded as the most ancient religious texts. The primary sacred texts of Hinduism are the Vedas: Rig Veda, Sama Veda, Yajur Veda and Atharva Veda. Most popular Hindu scriptures are the Mahabharata, Bhagavad Gita and Ramayan.
"When you hear about the Self, meditate upon the Self,
and finally realize the Self...
you come to understand everything in life."
--Brihadaranyaka Upanishad 4.5 We also provides many Indian regional calendars includes telugu calendar , tamil calendar and Oriya calendar. Regional calendars are available in online, PDF and image format for download and print. These calendar also shows the daily Panchangam for each day of 2016.