
Islamic Religious Calendar for 2019
Islamic festivals are the days celebrated by Muslims. Here we have provided the dates of the Islamic religious holidays for calendar year 2019. Some dates may vary slightly as they are determined by the lunar calendar. Islam was founded in the 7th century by Prophet Muhammad. Today this is the second largest religion in the world with more than 1.2 billion followers. The Quran is the sacred text of Islam. The Arabic word “Islam” means submission. Muslims believe that Prophet Muhammad is the final messenger from God. The goal of a Muslim’s life is to live in a way to please Allah (The God) so that one may gain enlightenment. The Five Pillars of Islam are:
   - SHAHADAH.: Faith - “There is no god except Allah, Muhammad is the messenger of Allah”. 
   - SALAH: Prayer - Praying five times a day. 
   - ZAKAH: Donate - Each year, Muslims are supposed to donate a fixed proportion of their savings for good deeds.
   - SAWM: Fasting - Fasting during the month of Ramadan. 
   - HAJJ: Pilgrimage - Making a pilgrimage to Mecca at least once in the lifetime of a Muslim, if it is affordable.